[{"question":" What can you use to visually distinguish between Play mode and Design mode in the editor?","options":[{"text":"The object inspector","correct":false},{"text":"Handles","correct":false},{"text":"Gizmos","correct":false},{"text":"Play mode tint","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" A developer executes the C# code below, which finds any game objects tagged as “enemy” in a start event. But the developer notices that, when executed, FindGameObjectsWithTag returns NULL even though the scene contains objects tagged as “Enemy”. What is a possible cause?","options":[{"text":"The objects are animated","correct":false},{"text":"The objects are on the UI layer","correct":false},{"text":"The objects are not named “Enemy”","correct":false},{"text":"The objects are deactivated","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What does this code sample achieve? Float Answer = Random.value \\* 10f;","options":[{"text":"It selects a random number that is less than 10","correct":false},{"text":"It selects a random number greater than 10","correct":false},{"text":"It selects a random number between 0 and 10","correct":false},{"text":"It selects a random number that is multiple of 10","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Unity scenes may be saved entirely in the YAML format. Why might you do this?","options":[{"text":"To reduce scene file size","correct":false},{"text":"To externally parse a scene and its objects","correct":false},{"text":"To optimize scene loading and unloading","correct":false},{"text":"To improve platform compatibility","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Orthographic cameras remove which visual effect?","options":[{"text":"Gamma color space","correct":false},{"text":"Depth of field","correct":false},{"text":"Foreshortening","correct":false},{"text":"Bloom","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What is Cinemachine Virtual Camera used for?","options":[{"text":"To override standard scene cameras with cinematic behaviours","correct":false},{"text":"To determine what cameras will see when arriving at specific locations","correct":false},{"text":"To create predefined camera presets to apply on standard cameras","correct":false},{"text":"To act as dummy cameras for fooling meshes into thinking they are being seen","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" What does the Microphone class save captured audio data as?","options":[{"text":"An audio clip asset","correct":false},{"text":"An MP3 file","correct":false},{"text":"A WAV file","correct":false},{"text":"An OGG file","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" Cinemachine offers tools for building gameplay behaviours. Which component makes spline based paths for moving objects?","options":[{"text":"Cinemachine Target Group","correct":false},{"text":"Cinemachine Smooth Path","correct":false},{"text":"Cinemachine Free Look","correct":false},{"text":"Cinemachine Brain","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":" When building assets like meshes for Unity. It is good practice to use which measurement unit?","options":[{"text":"Cubits","correct":false},{"text":"Feet","correct":false},{"text":"Inches","correct":false},{"text":"Meters","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". The Collaborate feature of Unity Teams empowers whom to do what?","options":[{"text":"Developers to contribute to the unity source code","correct":false},{"text":"Companies to raise money for projects through crowdfunding","correct":false},{"text":"Team members to save, share, and sync unity projects","correct":false},{"text":"Developers to integrate version control systems, like git, into projects","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". The Clear Flags property of the Camera components affects which behaviour?","options":[{"text":"How the camera renders UI objects on top of the scene","correct":false},{"text":"How the camera renders transparent objects by default","correct":false},{"text":"How the camera renders its background on each frame","correct":false},{"text":"How the camera occludes background objects","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the OnAnimatorMove event on MonoBehaviour objects commonly used for?","options":[{"text":"Detecting when an object moves","correct":false},{"text":"Updating a navigation agent in response to keyframe data","correct":false},{"text":"Replaying an animation when it has completed","correct":false},{"text":"Modifying the root motion of an animated object","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which MonoBehaviour method runs by default in Editor mode?","options":[{"text":"OnBecameInvisible","correct":false},{"text":"OnAnimatorMove","correct":false},{"text":"Reset","correct":false},{"text":"OnTriggerEnter","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". For the OnTriggerEnter function to invoke successfully on a collision between two objects, at least one must have which two components?","options":[{"text":"A Collider and a MeshRenderer","correct":false},{"text":"A Collider and a MeshFilter","correct":false},{"text":"A Rigidbody and a Collider","correct":false},{"text":"A MeshRenderer and a MeshFilter","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". UI elements, such as images and buttons, may be fixed at specific screen positions to build responsive interfaces. Which Unity features help achieve this?","options":[{"text":"Events and raycasts","correct":false},{"text":"Quaternions and Euler angles","correct":false},{"text":"Opacity and transparency","correct":false},{"text":"Anchors and pivots","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". The occlusion map of a material is often a grayscale image with pixels ranging between black and white. What does this map contribute to an object’s material?","options":[{"text":"White pixels reveal the detail map and black pixels reveal none","correct":false},{"text":"White pixels allow emission and black pixels allow none","correct":false},{"text":"White pixels receive shadows and black pixels receive none","correct":false},{"text":"White pixels receive full indirect illumination and black pixels receive none","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What can you use to organize different game objects into groups inside the Hierarchy panel?","options":[{"text":"Canvas objects","correct":false},{"text":"Event systems","correct":false},{"text":"Empty objects","correct":false},{"text":"Mesh renderers","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". The Project windows search box can filter the display of assets with text commands. Which command displays only texture assets?","options":[{"text":"T:mesh","correct":false},{"text":"T:texture","correct":false},{"text":"T:mesh","correct":false},{"text":"Show textures","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". A bullet game object is fired from a weapon and travels quickly through the scene using a RigidBody component. It sometimes passes through solid objects even though they have colliders. What is a reasonable strategy for correcting this?","options":[{"text":"Expand the collider size of all scene objects and the bullets to detect collisions with better time","correct":false},{"text":"Increase the Fixed Time Step value from the Project Settings dialog to change the frequency of the FixedUpdate event","correct":false},{"text":"Change the Collision Detection property of the Rigidbody to Continuous Dynamic or Continous Speculative","correct":false},{"text":"Enable the IsKinematic property of the Rigidbody","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Some material types may include normal map textures. What does a normal map achieve?","options":[{"text":"It programmatically reduced the polycount of your meshes.","correct":false},{"text":"It displaces mesh geometry with extrusion and bevels to generate higher-poly versions.","correct":false},{"text":"It creates the appearance of surface detail on mesh - like bumps, dents, and scratches","correct":false},{"text":"It is a level-of-detail system that progressively reduces a mesh’s polygons as a scene camera moves farther away from it","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". A SkinnedMeshRenderer component is attached automatically by Unity to some mesh objects when they are added to a scene. Which reason best explains why?","options":[{"text":"The mesh file contains bones and rig data","correct":false},{"text":"The game object also features an animator component","correct":false},{"text":"The game object is a Player-Controlled character","correct":false},{"text":"The mesh file contains a humanoid character","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which C# attribute can show a private variable in the object inspector?","options":[{"text":"Range","correct":false},{"text":"HideInInspector","correct":false},{"text":"Serializable","correct":false},{"text":"SerializedField","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is a technique for optimizing Unity UI elements?","options":[{"text":"Group static UI elements on one canvas, and dynamic elements on a separate canvas","correct":false},{"text":"Position all canvas objects to the world origin","correct":false},{"text":"Group as many UI elements as possible onto only one canvas","correct":false},{"text":"Divide the screen into multiple canvas objects, each sized to a quarter of the screen size","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does the C# Space attribute used below achieved?","options":[{"text":"It inserts 20 space characters as a default value into the string variable below","correct":false},{"text":"It inserts 20 pixels of margin on all edges around the variable inside the Object Inspector","correct":false},{"text":"It inserts 20 pixels of empty space above the variable inside the Object Inspector","correct":false},{"text":"It inserts 20 pixels of empty space below the variable inside the Object Inspector","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Every time you double-click a C# script file from the Project window, Unity prints the message below (or something very similar) to the console. What is a reasonable step in trying to solve this? Cannot start process because a file name has not been provided","options":[{"text":"Search the Project windows for all script files and then rename all of them","correct":false},{"text":"Set Visual Studio as the code default editor via the External Tools tab of the Preferences menu","correct":false},{"text":"Ensure you have specified a Play mode tint color from the Colors tab of the Preferences menu","correct":false},{"text":"Select the Script file, and then select Assets > Find references in Scene from the Application menu","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What is the Console windows useful for?","options":[{"text":"Viewing and editing text files","correct":false},{"text":"Downloading data packets and asset packages","correct":false},{"text":"Typing and executing command line instructions through a shell interface","correct":false},{"text":"Identifying errors in your script files and project","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Sprite atlas assets, large textures containing many smaller sprites, can be optimized by batching together what?","options":[{"text":"Sprites that are non animated","correct":false},{"text":"Sprites that appear together in game","correct":false},{"text":"Sprites using the same color palette","correct":false},{"text":"Sprites of the same dimensions","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You are making a game where you need to execute your own functions in response to critical animation events for a rigged character. Specifically, there are two events you must handle: when an animation state is entered and when it is exited in the Animator graph. Which class may be used to invoke your code when those two events happen?","options":[{"text":"AnimatorClipInfo","correct":false},{"text":"StateMachineBehaviour","correct":false},{"text":"AnimationInfo","correct":false},{"text":"AnimatorUtility","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How can you change the unique bundle identifier for a mobile build?","options":[{"text":"Select Assets > import Package, and then import the Cross-Platform Input Asset Package","correct":false},{"text":"Select Windows > Asset Management > Version Control, and then enter an identifier in the Source field","correct":false},{"text":"Select File > Build Settings. Then from the Build dialog box, select Android or iOS, and select the Bundle Identifier from the Compression Method drop down menu.","correct":false},{"text":"Select Edit > Project Settings > Player from the menu, and then expand the Other Settings tab","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Rigidbody components may be added to objects with colliders to make them affected by physical forces. What does the IsKinematic property achieve?","options":[{"text":"It removes gravity from an object but retains all other forces","correct":false},{"text":"It removes all physical forces from the object, except gravity","correct":false},{"text":"It converts the object into physical forces that affect other objects","correct":false},{"text":"It suspends physical forces on the object, allowing manual transofrmations","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". The primary directional light in a scene is linked by default to a procedural scene Skybox. What does the rotation of this light control?","options":[{"text":"The orientation of the Skybox","correct":false},{"text":"The night and day status of the skybox","correct":false},{"text":"The acoustics of all audio sources","correct":false},{"text":"The resolution of the skybox","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". You can combine quaternions together through which arithmetic operation?","options":[{"text":"Multiplication","correct":false},{"text":"Division","correct":false},{"text":"Addition","correct":false},{"text":"Subtraction","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Which feature generates binary tree data to optimize camera rendering in a scene?","options":[{"text":"Render textures","correct":false},{"text":"Navigation mesh","correct":false},{"text":"Profiler","correct":false},{"text":"Occlusion Culling","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". How does the Range C# attribute control the interaction behavior of numerical variables in the Object Inspector?","options":[{"text":"It restricts the variable value using a slider widget","correct":false},{"text":"It validates the variable values through a text box widget","correct":false},{"text":"It restricts the variable values using a color picker widget","correct":false},{"text":"It presents valid options in a drop down list","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". What does this code fragment do when attached to a rigged character?","options":[{"text":"It blends the characters head animation with a second predefined animation","correct":false},{"text":"It makes the characters head face toward the specified target","correct":false},{"text":"It returns the characters head back to a neutral position","correct":false},{"text":"It makes a game object face toward the characters head","correct":false}],"illustrator":"```\n    public Animator avatar;\n    public Transform lookAtObj;\n    void OnAnimatorIK(int layerIndex)\n    {\n        avatar.SetLookAtPosition(lookAtObj).position;\n        avatar.SetLookAtWeight(If);\n    }\n```"},{"question":". The variable Transform.forward is a Vector3 measured in what?","options":[{"text":"Local space","correct":false},{"text":"Innerspace","correct":false},{"text":"Normal space","correct":false},{"text":"World space","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". De-lighting is associated with which technology?","options":[{"text":"Virtual reality","correct":false},{"text":"Augmented reality","correct":false},{"text":"Motion capture","correct":false},{"text":"Photogrammetry","correct":false}],"illustrator":""},{"question":". Humanoid character assets, like NPCs and the player character, feature on Avatar object. Which statement best describes its purpose?","options":[{"text":"Avatars define parameter sets for facial muscle blendshapes","correct":false},{"text":"Avatar facilitate animation retargeting across different humanoid characters","correct":false},{"text":"Avatar define IK data for animated characters","correct":false},{"text":"Avatars describe how textures map on deforming objects during animation","correct":false}],"illustrator":""}]